<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc>
    <__XppWrappedObject>
        <summary>
        The XppWrappedObject class.
        </summary>
    </__XppWrappedObject>
    <Abstract.ClassName>
        <summary>Retrieves the name of the class an object belongs to.</summary>
        <returns>The method returns a character string representing the name of a class.</returns>
    </Abstract.ClassName>
    <Abstract.ClassObject>
        <summary>Retrieves the class object (System.Type) of a class.</summary>
        <returns>The method returns the class object of a class.</returns>
        <remarks>The X# XPP implementation returns a System.Type object as class object.</remarks>
    </Abstract.ClassObject>
    <Abstract.GetNoIVar>
        <summary>Handles access operations to undefined instance variables. </summary>
        <param name="cName">The fieldname to access.</param>
        <returns/>
    </Abstract.GetNoIVar>
    <Abstract.IsDerivedFrom>
        <summary>Checks if an object belongs to or is derived from a particular class.</summary>
        <param name="uParent">A character string containing the name of the class an object belongs to or is derived from. Alternatively, the class object (System.Type) can be passed instead of the class name.</param>
        <returns>The method returns .T. (true) if the object executing the method belongs to or is derived from the specified class. </returns>
        <remarks>This method is used to check if an unknown object has features of a known class. This is especially useful for event driven programming or when classes are inherited from other classes.</remarks>
    </Abstract.IsDerivedFrom>
  <Abstract.NoMethod>
    <summary>Handles calls to undefined methods.</summary>
    <param name="uParams">The parameters to send to the method.</param>
    <returns>The return value will be interpreted as the return value of the called undefined method. </returns>
    <remarks>If an undefined method is called, a runtime error is raised.</remarks>

  </Abstract.NoMethod>
  <Abstract.Notify>
        <summary>Receives notifications from DatabaseEngines </summary>
        <param name="nEvent">This parameter receives a numeric value that corresponds with a constant listed in APPEVENT.CH.</param>
        <param name="nNotification">The second parameter identifies the situation for which an object is notified. The file DMLB.CH lists define constants that can be used to test in a program which situation occurred. </param>
        <remarks>There is no need in X# to include the header files. The defines are included as part of the X# runtime.</remarks>
    </Abstract.Notify>
    <Abstract.SetNoIVar>
        <summary>Handles assign operations to undefined instance variables. </summary>
        <param name="cName">The fieldname to assign.</param>
        <param name="uValue">The value of an assignment. </param>
        <returns>The return value of the method is ignored.</returns>
    </Abstract.SetNoIVar>
    <ClassCreate>
        <summary>Create a class dynamically.</summary>
        <returns>The class object.</returns>
    </ClassCreate>
    <ClassDestroy>
        <summary>Remove the class object of class. </summary>
        <param name="uObject">The name of the class whose class object should be deleted, or the class object.</param>
        <returns>The return value is .T. (true) when the class object is removed from memory, otherwise it is .F. (false). </returns>
        <remarks>The function ClassDestroy() removes the class object of a dynamically created class from main memory.
        Dynamic classes are created during runtime by the ClassCreate() function. They are unknown at compile time.
        Therefore, they do not have a class function and are represented at runtime of a program only by a class object. <br/>
        When a program uses a dynamic class, the corresponding class object should be removed from main memory when the class
        is no longer needed. Otherwise, the class object remains in memory and can be retrieved by the ClassObject() function at any time.<br/>
        <b>Note</b>In X# classes are never really freed from memory. The .Net framework does not allow that. ClassDestroy() does remove the class
        from the list of active classes. If you recreate the same class later with the same structure then the class definition from the previous
        defintion is reused.</remarks>
    </ClassDestroy>
    <ClassHelpers.FindClass>
        <summary>
        Find the ClassObject for a class
        </summary>
        <param name="cClassName"/>
        <param name="lIncludeDeleted"/>
        <returns/>
    </ClassHelpers.FindClass>
    <ClassHelpers.FullNameTypeFilter>
        Delegate to filter types in the DynamicAssembly
    </ClassHelpers.FullNameTypeFilter>
    <ClassObject>
        <summary>Retrieves the class object of class. </summary>
        <param name="cClassName">The name of the class whose class object should be returned. </param>
        <returns>The function returns the class object of the class with the name &lt;cClassName&gt;.
        The return value is NULL_OBJECT when the class does not exist. </returns>
    </ClassObject>
    <ClassObject>
    <summary>
      This class returns the ClasssObject for classes, both the classes created at compile time
      as well as the classes created at runtime.
      This object allows to access static members and methods late bound
      Such as <code>Example():Fieldname</code>
    </summary>
  </ClassObject>
    <ClassObject.New>
        <summary>
        Create a new instance of the class.
        </summary>
        <returns>new object</returns>
    </ClassObject.New>
    <ClassObject.NoIvarGet>
        <summary>
        Late bound access to class/static vars
        </summary>
        <param name="cName">Name of the property/field to read</param>
        <returns>the result of reading the property or field</returns>
    </ClassObject.NoIvarGet>
    <ClassObject.NoIvarPut>
        <summary>
        Late bound assign for class/static vars
        </summary>
        <param name="cName">Name of the property/field to update</param>
        <param name="uValue">New value for the property</param>
        <returns>uValue</returns>
    </ClassObject.NoIvarPut>
    <ClassObject.NoMethod>
        <summary>
        Late bound calls for Static/Class methods.
        </summary>
        <returns>Result of Method Call</returns>
    </ClassObject.NoMethod>
    <DataObject>
    <summary>
      The Xbase++ DataObject class.
    </summary>
  </DataObject>
    <DataObject.Copy>
        <summary>Creates a dependent shallow copy of this instance </summary>
        <returns>This method returns the new DataObject instance. </returns>
    </DataObject.Copy>
    <DataObject.DefineMethod>
        <summary>Defines a dynamic method. </summary>
        <param name="cName">The name of the method to be defined.</param>
        <param name="uAction">A Function name or codeblock that must be executed when the method is called.</param>
        <returns>This method returns the DataObject (self).</returns>
        <remarks>Dynamic methods in X# are called from the NoMethod method inside the DataObject class.</remarks>
    </DataObject.DefineMethod>
    <DataObject.IsMemberVar>
        <summary>
        Checks if the object has a particular member variable
        </summary>
        <param name="cName">is a character string containing the symbolic identifier of a member variable.</param>
        <returns>The return value is .T. (true) if the object has the member variable &lt;cVarName&gt;, otherwise it returns .F. (false). </returns>
    </DataObject.IsMemberVar>
    <DataObject.Merge>
        <summary>Merges exported member variables from another object into this instance.</summary>
        <param name="oNewObject">DataObject to copy the member variables from.</param>
        <param name="cMessagePrefix">Optional prefix that will be added to all fields in the DataObject.</param>
        <returns>This method returns the DataObject (self).</returns>
    </DataObject.Merge>
    <DbCargo>
        <summary>Attaches an arbitrary value to a used work area </summary>
        <param name="xNewValue">the value to attach to a work area. </param>
        <returns>The function returns the value attached to a work area before the function is called. </returns>
        <remarks>The function DbCargo() attaches an arbitrary value to a used work area. The value remains in the work area,
        In this way, user defined data can be bound to a particular work area. Attached data is discarded when the workarea
        is closed.</remarks>
    </DbCargo>
    <DbDescend>
        <summary>Checks if the order for navigation is descending </summary>
        <returns>The return value of DbDescend() is TRUE when the in the current work area is descending, otherwise FALSE is returned. </returns>
        <remarks>The function DbDescend() tests if the order in the current work area is descending.
        Refer to DbSetDescend() for more information about reversing the navigational order.
        </remarks>
        <seealso cref="DbSetDescend">DbSetDescend()</seealso>
    </DbDescend>
    <DbSetDescend>
        <summary>Reverses the navigational order of a work area.</summary>
        <param name="lNewDescend">A logical value. When TRUE the navigational order in the current work area is set to descending, FALSE sets the order to ascending. </param>
        <returns>The return value of DbSetDescend() is the previous setting for DbSetDescend().</returns>
        <remarks>The function DbSetDescend() is used to quickly change the order in a work area from ascending to descending and vice versa
        without the need to create a corresponding index. When TRUE is passed to the function, the order is reversed, i.e. all functions and
        commands that move the record pointer are inverted. DbGoTop() becomes DbGoBottom(), DbSkip(1) becomes DbSkip(-1), EOF becomes BOF() etc.
        <note type="tip"> Not all RDDs support switching the order at runtime </note></remarks>
        <seealso cref="DbDescend">DbDescend()</seealso>
    </DbSetDescend>
    <DynamicClassObject>
    <summary>The worker class to help create classes at runtime.</summary>
  </DynamicClassObject>
<LOCKING_EXCLUSIVE>
        Specifies the locking behaviour inside/outside of transactions
    </LOCKING_EXCLUSIVE>
    <PosAlpha>
        <summary>Retrieves the 1 based position of the first letter in a string. </summary>
        <returns>Returns the position of the first letter in a string as a numeric value, or ZERO when there is no uppercase letter in the string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to check</param>
        <param name="lNoLetter">When TRUE is passed then the first character is returned which is not a not a letter. Defaults to FALSE.</param>
        <param name="nIgnoreCharsFromLeft">Number of characters that must be ignored. Defaults to 0.</param>
        <remarks>In X# A letter is defined as a character for which the Char.IsLetter() method returns TRUE.
        If <paramref name="lNoLetter"/> is set to TRUE the function returns the position of the first character which is not a letter. </remarks>
        <seealso cref="PosUpper"/>
        <seealso cref="PosLower"/>
    </PosAlpha>
    <PosChar>
        <summary>Replaces a single character at a specified position in a string. </summary>
        <returns>Returns the modified string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to check</param>
        <param name="uChar">The new character to insert into the string</param>
        <param name="nPosition">1 based position to change. Defaults to Len(<paramref name="cString"/>).</param>
        <seealso cref="PosDel"/>
        <seealso cref="PosIns"/>
        <seealso cref="PosRepl"/>
    </PosChar>
    <PosDel>
        <summary>Removes characters at a specified position in a string. </summary>
        <returns>Returns the modified string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to check</param>
        <param name="nStartPos">1 based position to start deleting from. Defaults to Len(<paramref name="cString"/>).</param>
        <param name="nDeleteLen">The number of characters to delete.</param>
        <seealso cref="PosChar"/>
        <seealso cref="PosIns"/>
        <seealso cref="PosRepl"/>
    </PosDel>
    <PosIns>
        <summary>Inserts a character string into a string at a specified position.  </summary>
        <returns>Returns the modified string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to update</param>
        <param name="cInsertString">The string to insert</param>
        <param name="nPosition">1 based position where the string must be inserted. Defaults to Len(<paramref name="cString"/>)+1.</param>
        <seealso cref="PosChar"/>
        <seealso cref="PosDel"/>
        <seealso cref="PosRepl"/>
    </PosIns>
    <PosLower>
        <summary>Retrieves the 1 based position of the first lower case letter in a string. </summary>
        <returns>Returns the position of the first lower case letter in a string as a numeric value, or ZERO when there is no uppercase letter in the string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to check</param>
        <param name="lNoLetter">When TRUE is passed then the first character is returned which is not changed by function Upper(). Defaults to FALSE.</param>
        <param name="nIgnoreCharsFromLeft">Number of characters that must be ignored. Defaults to 0.</param>
        <remarks>In X# A letter is defined as a character for which the Char.IsLetter() method returns TRUE.
        If <paramref name="lNoLetter"/> is set to TRUE  the function returns the position of the first character which is not a letter. </remarks>
        <seealso cref="PosUpper"/>
        <seealso cref="PosAlpha"/>
    </PosLower>
    <PosRepl>
        <summary>Inserts a character string into a string at a specified position.</summary>
        <returns>Returns the modified string.</returns>
        <param name="cString">String to update</param>
        <param name="cReplace">The string to insert.</param>
        <param name="nStartPos">1 based position where the string must be inserted. </param>
        <remarks>If the parameter <paramref name="nStartPos"/> is not specified the function
        replaces Len( <paramref name="cReplace"/> ) characters at the end of <paramref name="cString"/>.</remarks>
        <seealso cref="PosChar"/>
        <seealso cref="PosDel"/>
        <seealso cref="PosIns"/>
    </PosRepl>
    <PosUpper>
        <summary>Retrieves the 1 based position of the first upper case letter in a string. </summary>
        <returns>Returns the position of the first upper case letter in a string as a numeric value, or ZERO when there is no uppercase letter in the string. </returns>
        <param name="cString">String to check</param>
        <param name="lNoLetter">When TRUE is passed then the first character is returned which is not changed by function Lower(). Defaults to FALSE.</param>
        <param name="nIgnoreCharsFromLeft">Number of characters that must be ignored. Defaults to 0.</param>
        <remarks>In X# A letter is defined as a character for which the Char.IsLetter() method returns TRUE.
        If <paramref name="lNoLetter"/> is set to TRUE  the function returns the position of the first character which is not a letter. </remarks>
        <seealso cref="PosLower"/>
        <seealso cref="PosAlpha"/>
    </PosUpper>
    <SetCollation>
        <summary>Query current and/or set new active collation.</summary>
        <param name="nCollation">the numeric identifier for the collation table to be selected. Must be one of the values from the XppCollations enum of a simple number</param>
        <returns>The numeric identifier of the active collation table </returns>
        <seealso cref="XppCollations"/>
        <seealso cref="SetCollationTable"/>
    </SetCollation>
    <SetCollationTable>
        <summary>Query current and/or set user defined collation table .</summary>
        <param name="nCollation">the numeric identifier for the collation table to be selected. Must be one of the values from the XppCollations enum of a simple number</param>
        <param name="aTable">a one dimensional array with 256 elements. It must contain numeric values representing the weighing factors for single characters.
        The ASCII value of a character plus 1 defines the array element that contains the weighing factor for that character. </param>
        <returns>a one dimensional array holding the weighing factors of characters for the active collation. </returns>
        <seealso cref="XppCollations"/>
        <seealso cref="SetCollation"/>
    </SetCollationTable>
    <StaticClassObject>
    <summary>
      This class returns the ClasssObject for classes created at compile time (Static classes)
      This object allows to access static members and methods late bound
      Such as <code>Example():Fieldname</code>
    </summary>
  </StaticClassObject>
  <XAction>
        <summary>Helper class that stores actions (codeblocks) for XML nodes</summary>
    </XAction>
    <XAction.Block>
        <summary>Codeblock to run for the action</summary>
    </XAction.Block>
    <XAction.Name>
        <summary>XML node name for which the action runs.</summary>
    </XAction.Name>
    <xbeK_UP>
        ///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    </xbeK_UP>
    <XDocument>
        <summary>Helper class that is used by the XML functions</summary>
    </XDocument>
    <XDocument.AsXmlArray>
        <summary>Return the children of a node as a XPP specific XML array</summary>
    </XDocument.AsXmlArray>
    <XDocument.ClearActions>
        <summary>Clear all actions on a document</summary>
    </XDocument.ClearActions>
    <XDocument.ClearAllErrors>
        <summary>Clear all errors</summary>
    </XDocument.ClearAllErrors>
    <XDocument.Close>
        <summary>CLose an opened XML document</summary>
    </XDocument.Close>
    <XDocument.CloseAllDocuments>
        <summary>Close all open document</summary>
    </XDocument.CloseAllDocuments>
    <XDocument.DocHandle>
        <summary>Unique handle for the document.</summary>
    </XDocument.DocHandle>
    <XDocument.FindChildTag>
        <summary>Find a child tag in an XML Node</summary>
    </XDocument.FindChildTag>
    <XDocument.FindError>
        <summary>Find error by ID</summary>
    </XDocument.FindError>
    <XDocument.FindFirstChildTag>
        <summary>Find a child tag in an XML Node</summary>
    </XDocument.FindFirstChildTag>
    <XDocument.FindNode>
        <summary>Get XML node and document by ID</summary>
    </XDocument.FindNode>
    <XDocument.FindParent>
        <summary>Get ID for the parent of an XML node</summary>
    </XDocument.FindParent>
    <XDocument.FindTag>
        <summary>Get a list of the tags in an XML Node</summary>
    </XDocument.FindTag>
    <XDocument.GetDocument>
        <summary>Find an open XDocument object by its unique handle</summary>
    </XDocument.GetDocument>
    <XDocument.GetErrors>
        <summary>Get list of all errors</summary>
    </XDocument.GetErrors>
    <XDocument.GetErrorsForDocument>
        <summary>Get error for a specific document</summary>
    </XDocument.GetErrorsForDocument>
    <XDocument.Initialize>
        <summary>Initialize the static variables</summary>
    </XDocument.Initialize>
    <XDocument.NewHandle>
        <summary>Allocate new XDocument handle</summary>
    </XDocument.NewHandle>
    <XDocument.OpenFile>
        <summary>Open an XML File</summary>
    </XDocument.OpenFile>
    <XDocument.OpenText>
        <summary>Open a XML document from a string</summary>
    </XDocument.OpenText>
    <XDocument.PerformActions>
        <summary>Perform actions on an XML node.</summary>
    </XDocument.PerformActions>
    <XDocument.Process>
        <summary>Process an opened XML document</summary>
    </XDocument.Process>
    <XDocument.ProcessNodes>
        <summary>Loop through all the actions and process each node that matches the actions</summary>
    </XDocument.ProcessNodes>
    <XDocument.RegisterError>
        <summary/>
    </XDocument.RegisterError>
    <XDocument.SelectNodes>
        <summary>Select Nodes via XPath selection </summary>
    </XDocument.SelectNodes>
    <XDocument.SetAction>
        <summary>Set an action on a XML node</summary>
    </XDocument.SetAction>
    <XDocument.WalkNode>
        <summary>Walk all nodes and add them to the collections on the document class</summary>
    </XDocument.WalkNode>
    <XError>
        <summary>Helper class that stores errors for an XML document</summary>
    </XError>
    <XError.Additional>
        <summary>Additional info about the error.</summary>
    </XError.Additional>
    <XError.Column>
        <summary>Column where the error occurred.</summary>
    </XError.Column>
    <XError.DocHandle>
        <summary>Document Handle for which the error occurred.</summary>
    </XError.DocHandle>
    <XError.FileName>
        <summary>Filename where the error occurred.</summary>
    </XError.FileName>
    <XError.Handle>
        <summary>Error Handle.</summary>
    </XError.Handle>
    <XError.Id>
        <summary>Id for the node where the error occurred.</summary>
    </XError.Id>
    <XError.Line>
        <summary>Linenumber where the error occurred.</summary>
    </XError.Line>
    <XError.ToArray>
        <summary>Convert error object to XBase++ compatible error array.</summary>
    </XError.ToArray>
  <XMLDocClearErrors>
        <summary>Clear all global XML Errors.</summary>
        <returns>Allways returns .T. (true).</returns>
        <remarks>Closes all XML errors that are not linked to a XML document.</remarks>
    </XMLDocClearErrors>
    <XMLDocClose>
        <summary>Close an XML document. </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle"/>
        <returns>Returns .T. (true) if the document is successfully closed and .F. (false) otherwise.</returns>
        <remarks>Closes XML document and releases system resources.</remarks>
    </XMLDocClose>
    <XMLDocCloseAll>
        <summary>Close all open XML documents.</summary>
        <returns>Allways returns .T. (true).</returns>
        <remarks>Closes all XML documents, clears all errors and releases system resources.</remarks>
    </XMLDocCloseAll>
    <XMLDocGetErrorList>
        <summary>Get array of error descriptions. </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle of an XML document. Use this handle if a valid document handle was returned by an doc open function. </param>
        <param name="nErrHandle">Numeric error handle returned XMLOpenDocFile() or XMLOpenDocString(). Use this handle to retrieve errors produced by an open function, where an invalid document handle was returned. </param>
        <returns>Returns a two-dimensional array holding error information, or NULL_ARRAY if no error occurred.</returns>
        <remarks/>
    </XMLDocGetErrorList>
    <XMLDocGetRootTag>
        <summary>Get the root tag of an XML document. </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle of an XML document. </param>
        <returns>The function returns the numeric handle of an XML document. </returns>
        <remarks>This function returns the root tag of an XML document.
        The root tag is a tag that is created by the parser as the root node of the XML document tree.
        i.e. a document has always a root tag, even if the XML file (or string) is empty.
        This function provides for the starting point when traversing a document tree.
        See function XMLGetTag() for more information about an XML tag. </remarks>
    </XMLDocGetRootTag>
    <XMLDocOpenFile>
        <summary>Open an XML document. </summary>
        <param name="cFileName">Name of an XML file to be parsed.</param>
        <returns>Returns a non-zero numeric handle for the document, or 0 if there are not enough system resources
        for the parser, or when the file cannot be opened, read or parsed. The handle returned by this function must be used in subsequent calls to other XMLDoc..() functions. </returns>
        <remarks>XMLDocOpenFile() opens a new XML document. It allocates system resources for the parser, opens and reads the file and parses it contents.
        While parsing a document, a tree is build by the parsing engine. </remarks>
    </XMLDocOpenFile>
    <XMLDocOpenFile_2>
        <summary>Open an XML document. </summary>
        <param name="cFileName">Name of an XML file to be parsed.</param>
        <param name="nErrHandle">Pass a variable by reference which receives an error handle if errors were recorded.</param>
        <returns>Returns a non-zero numeric handle for the document, or 0 if there are not enough system resources
        for the parser, or when the file cannot be opened, read or parsed. The handle returned by this function must be used in subsequent calls to other XMLDoc..() functions. </returns>
        <remarks>XMLDocOpenFile() opens a new XML document. It allocates system resources for the parser, opens and reads the file and parses it contents.
        While parsing a document, a tree is build by the parsing engine. </remarks>
    </XMLDocOpenFile_2>
    <XMLDocOpenString>
        <summary>Create XML document from a string. </summary>
        <param name="cXMLString">Character string representing a valid XML document. </param>
        <param name="nErrHandle">Pass a variable by reference which receives an error handle if errors were recorded.</param>
        <returns>Returns a non-zero handle for the passed string or 0 if there are not enough system resources for the parser,
        or when the string does not contain valid XML code. The handle returned by this function must be used in subsequent
        calls to other XMLDoc..() functions. <br/>
        If the function returns 0, more information can be obtained by calling XMLDocGetErrorList(, <paramref name="nErrHandle"/> ). </returns>
        <remarks>Invokes the XML parser engine which parsed the passed string and builds the internal tree structure. </remarks>
    </XMLDocOpenString>
    <XMLDocOpenString_2>
        <summary>Create XML document from a string. </summary>
        <param name="cXMLString">Character string representing a valid XML document. </param>
        <param name="nErrHandle">Pass a variable by reference which receives an error handle if errors were recorded.</param>
        <returns>Returns a non-zero handle for the passed string or 0 if there are not enough system resources for the parser,
        or when the string does not contain valid XML code. The handle returned by this function must be used in subsequent
        calls to other XMLDoc..() functions. <br/>
        If the function returns 0, more information can be obtained by calling XMLDocGetErrorList(,<paramref name="nErrHandle"/>). </returns>
        <remarks>Invokes the XML parser engine which parsed the passed string and builds the internal tree structure. </remarks>
    </XMLDocOpenString_2>
    <XMLDocProcess>
        <summary>Execute action code blocks for all tags. </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle for an XML document. </param>
        <returns>Returns .T. (true) if all action code blocks have been executed successfully or .F. (false) otherwise.</returns>
        <remarks>This function executes all action code blocks registered for an XML document using XMLDocSetAction().</remarks>
    </XMLDocProcess>
    <XMLDocResetAction>
        <summary>Releases the action code blocks defined with XMLDocSetAction(). </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle of an XML document.</param>
        <returns>Returns .T. (true) if the document handle is a valid and .F. (false) otherwise.</returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to release all action code blocks defined for all nodes of an XML document</remarks>
    </XMLDocResetAction>
    <XMLDocSetAction>
        <summary>Set action code blocks for specific tags.</summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle of the XML document.</param>
        <param name="cNode">A character string defining one or more nodes in the XML document. See description below.</param>
        <param name="bCallback">A code block to be associated with the nodes in an XML document specified with <paramref name="cNode"/>.</param>
        <returns>The function returns the number of tags, or nodes, matching the string <paramref name="cNode"/>.</returns>
        <remarks/>
    </XMLDocSetAction>
    <XMLGetAttribute>
        <summary>Get attribute value of an XML tag. </summary>
        <param name="nTagHandle">Numeric handle of the XML tag. </param>
        <param name="cAttributeName">Character string containing the name of the tag attribute whose value is searched.</param>
        <returns>Returns a string representing the value of a tag attribute or NULL_STRING if no attribute with the given name exists. </returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to obtain values of individual XML tag attributes by attribute name. </remarks>
    </XMLGetAttribute>
    <XMLGetChild>
        <summary>Get child of XML tag. </summary>
        <param name="nTagHandle">Numeric handle for the XML tag. </param>
        <param name="cChildTagName">The tag name of the child to search.</param>
        <returns>Returns the numeric handle of the first child matching the specified name, or 0 if no child with the given name exists. </returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to retrieve the first child tag of an XML tag matching the name
        specified with the second parameter. The XMLGetChildren() function can be used to obtain ALL child tags having a specific name. </remarks>
    </XMLGetChild>
    <XMLGetChildren>
        <summary>Get array of children of an XML tag. </summary>
        <param name="nTagHandle">Numeric handle for the XML tag. </param>
        <param name="cChildTagName">The tag name of the child tags to search.</param>
        <returns>Returns an array of child handles matching the name specified as second parameter, or 0 if no child with the given name exists.</returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to retrieve all child tags having the tag name specified with the second parameter.</remarks>
    </XMLGetChildren>
    <XMLGetParent>
        <summary>Get parent of XML tag.</summary>
        <param name="nTagHandle">Numeric handle for the XML tag.</param>
        <returns>Returns the numeric handle of the parent tag or 0 if <paramref name="nTagHandle"/> doesn't have a parent tag. </returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to retrieve the parent tag of an XML tag. Every tag has only one parent, except the document root tag which has no parent tag. </remarks>
    </XMLGetParent>
    <XMLGetTag>
        <summary>Get members of an XML tag node. </summary>
        <param name="nTagHandle">Numeric handle of an XML tag. </param>
        <param name="aTagMember">If the function returns successfully, this parameter contains an array with all members of the tag.
        The parameter must be passed by reference. Single elements of the array can be accessed using constants listed below.</param>
        <returns>Returns .T. (true) if the tag is a valid tag and .F. (false) otherwise.</returns>
        <remarks>This function is used to retrieve all members of an XML tag node.
        The elements are the same as in Xbase++, and an extra 6th element has been added that contains the XmlNode object. </remarks>
    </XMLGetTag>
    <XMLSelectNodes>
        <summary>Select specific nodes via xpath. </summary>
        <param name="nDocHandle">Numeric handle for an XML document. </param>
        <param name="cSelect">XPath select statement. </param>
        <param name="aTagHandles">Output array </param>
        <returns>Returns .T. (true) nDocHandle is recognized or .F. (false) otherwise.</returns>
    </XMLSelectNodes>
    <XppCollations>
        <summary>List of possible values for XBase++ collations</summary>
        <remarks>The System enumeration value is represented by 2 different sort orders, depending on the current Ansi or Charmode setting.</remarks>
    </XppCollations>
  </doc>
