<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-10-09T20:39:49.264+02:00" lasteditedby="Eva" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Solution</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Solution</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Visual Studio organizes your source code in Solutions and in one or more projects.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A solution is a container for one or more related projects, along with build information, Visual Studio window settings, and any miscellaneous files that are not associated with a particular project. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A solution is described by a text file (extension .sln) with its own unique format; it is not intended to be edited by hand.</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">Visual Studio uses two file types (.sln and .suo) to store settings for solutions:</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="3" colcount="3">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Extension</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Name</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Description</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">.sln</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Visual Studio Solution</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Organizes projects, project items, and solution items in the solution.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">.suo</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Solution User Options</para>
        </td>
        <td style="vertical-align:middle;">
          <para styleclass="Body Text">Stores user-level settings and customizations, such as breakpoints.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Different projects in Visual Studio may target different development languages. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">It is very well possible to use C# and X# projects next to each other in the same solutions.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can also set dependency relations between projects for different development languages without problems.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Visual Studio will automatically determine the order in which projects must be build.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If you want, you can control this order by opening the Solution Properties dialog (right click on the Solution node in the Solution Explorer and choose &quot;Properties&quot;).</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The image below shows the Solution Properties dialog for the X# runtime solution.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">On this dialog you can also specify which project should be the &quot;start-up project&quot; when you start debugging inside Visual Studio. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Additionally, as shown, you can launch multiple projects simultaneously.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The &quot;Action&quot; combo allows you to choose whether to Start a program or to start Debugging a program when launching the debugger inside Visual Studio.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="SolutionProperties.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">On the &quot;Project Dependencies&quot; tab page, you can define the dependencies between projects.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="SolutionDependencies.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">In this dialog, you can see that two projects are already marked with a checkboxes. These projects are listed as references in the XSharp.VO project.</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">Other projects have a gray checkbox, which means that they depend on XSharp.VO, so you cannot make XSharp.VO dependent on them, as that would create a circular dependency. Projects with a white checkbox can be added to the &quot;Depends on:&quot; list for XSharp.VO if desired, which would mean that Visual Studio would always build them before building XSharp.VO. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">From this dialog, you can also open the &quot;Configuration Manager&quot; to maintain the various Configurations (typically Debug and Release) and different &quot;Platforms&quot;. By default, there is only one Platform called &quot;AnyCpu&quot;, but if your project contains C++ code, you may also have x86 and x64 platforms. The configuration manager can also be accessed through the Visual Studio Build menu.</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">Refer to the next chapter for more information about build configurations.</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
