<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Popup" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>__IncludeStrongTyping</title>
  <body>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Heading1">Strongly &#160;typed Methods</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">In addition to &lt;%APP%&gt; untyped method implementation, <text styleclass="Bold">strong typing</text> of method parameters and return values is now supported, providing you with a mechanism through which highly stable code can be obtained. &#160;The type information supplied enables the compiler to perform the necessary type checking and, thus, guarantee a much higher stable code quality.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A further benefit obtained by utilizing strongly typed methods is that of performance. &#160;The implementation of typed methods presumes that when the programmer employs strongly typed messages, the compiler can effectively perform an <text styleclass="Bold">early binding</text> for the respective methods invocation. &#160;As a result of this implementation, typed methods invocations are somewhat faster than the respective untyped counterparts. &#160;These advantages are, however, attained at the price of losing the flexibility which untyped methods offer.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">It is, therefore, important to remember that interchangeably using both the typed and the untyped versions of a particular methods in an inheritance chain is neither permissible nor possible.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">&lt;%APP%&gt; allows strong typing of METHODs, ACCESSes and ASSIGNs. &#160;The programmer accomplishes the specification of the strongly typed methods with &lt;%APP%&gt; in two steps:</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">1.<tab />A mandatory declaration of the typed method is given in its respective class.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab />This declaration is reponsible for declaring the order of the methods in the so-called virtual table which &lt;%APP%&gt; employs for the invocation of typed methods. &#160;A re-declaration of a method in a subclass is NOT permissible, since it would cause abiguity for the compiler.</para>
    <para styleclass="List">2.<tab />Define the strongly typed method. &#160;</para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab />Unlike strongly typed functions, method typing requires strongly typing of the method arguments, the method return value AND speficying a valid calling convention. &#160;<br/>The following calling conventions are valid for typed methods: STRICT, PASCAL or CALLBACK.</para>
  </body>
</topic>
