<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Popup" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>__IncludeMethodParameters</title>
  <body>
    <para styleclass="List">TypeParameters<tab/>This is supported for methods with generic type arguments. This something like &lt;T&gt; for a method with one type parameter named T. Usually one of the parameters in the parameter list is then also of type T.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">&lt;idParam&gt;<tab/>A method parameter variable.  A variable specified in this manner is automatically declared local.  These variables, also called formal parameters, are used to receive arguments that you pass when you call the function.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">AS | REF &lt;idType&gt;<tab/>Specifies the data type of the parameter variable (called strong typing).  AS indicates that the parameter must be passed by value, and REF indicates that it must be passed by reference with the @ operator.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><snippet src="__typeList" inline="false"/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><snippet src="__asType" inline="false"/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab/>Note   If you declare the return type of a method you must also strong type its parameters, specify the calling convention and you need to declare the method in the <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="command_CLASS">CLASS</link> declaration. See section about strong typed methods below.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">TypeParameterConstraints<tab/>Here you can specify constraints for the Type parameters, such as WHERE T IS SomeName or WHERE T IS New</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><snippet src="__callingconvention" inline="false"/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><tab/></para>
    <para styleclass="List">CLASS &lt;idClass&gt;<tab/>The class to which this method belongs. This clause is mandatory for entities declared outside of a CLASS .. END CLASS construct.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">EXPORT LOCAL<tab/>This clause is allowed by X# but ignored.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
