<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>BSD</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">BSD</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The Antlr source that we have used in our product is published under the BSD license. The full text of this license is:</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">[The &quot;BSD license&quot;]</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">Copyright (c) 2015 Terence Parr, Sam Harwell</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">All rights reserved.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">are met:</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> 1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> &#160; &#160;notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> 2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> &#160; &#160;notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> &#160; &#160;documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> 3. The name of the author may not be used to endorse or promote products</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"> &#160; &#160;derived from this software without specific prior written permission.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHOR ``AS IS&apos;&apos; AND ANY EXPRESS OR</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT,</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE,</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">(INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example">THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. </para>
  </body>
</topic>
