<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>GATHER Command</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Commands</keyword>
    <keyword>Fields<keyword>assigning new values</keyword></keyword>
    <keyword>GATHER command</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">GATHER Command &#160;(FoxPro)</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><snippet src="__CommandInclude" inline="false"/></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1">Purpose</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">Replaces the data in the current record of the currently selected table with data from an array, a set of variables, or an object.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1">Syntax</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code with box">GATHER FROM ArrayName | MEMVAR | NAME ObjectName<br/> &#160; [FIELDS FieldList | FIELDS LIKE Skeleton | FIELDS EXCEPT Skeleton]<br/> &#160; [MEMO]</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1">Arguments</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="List"><snippet src="__FoxFieldList" inline="false"/></para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">FROM &lt;ArrayName&gt;<tab />Specifies the array whose data replaces the data in the current record. The contents of the elements of the array, starting with the first element, replace the contents of the corresponding fields of the record. The contents of the first array element replace the first field of the record; the contents of the second array element replace the second field, and so on.<br/>If the array has fewer elements than the table has fields, the additional fields are ignored. If the array has more elements than the table has fields, the additional array elements are ignored. </para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"><tab /></para>
    <para styleclass="List">MEMVAR<tab />Specifies the variables or array from which data is copied to the current record. Data is transferred from the variable to the field that has the same name as the variable. The contents of a field are not replaced if a variable doesn&apos;t exist with the same name as the field.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">NAME &lt;ObjectName&gt;<tab />Specifies an object whose properties have the same names as fields in the table. The contents of each field are replaced by the value of the property with the same names as the fields. The contents of a field are not replaced if a property doesn&apos;t exist with the same name as the field.</para>
    <para styleclass="List"></para>
    <para styleclass="List">MEMO<tab /><text styleclass="Body Text">Specifies that the contents of memo or Blob fields are replaced with the contents or array elements or variables. If you omit MEMO, memo and Blob fields are skipped when GATHER replaces the contents of fields with the contents of an array or variable. General and picture fields are always ignored in GATHER, even if you include the MEMO keyword.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1">See Also</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Command_APPEND_FROM_ARRAY">APPEND FROM ARRAY</link>, <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="command_COPY_TO_ARRAY">COPY TO ARRAY</link>, <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Command_SCATTER">SCATTER</link></para>
  </body>
</topic>
