<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Known Issues</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Known Issues</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The current build of the X# compiler can compile the Vulcan SDK without changes, except for some obvious errors in the Vulcan SDK that Vulcan did not find!</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">We consider the Vulcan Compatibility of the compiler finished. All Vulcan code should compile without problems now.<br/>The next builds of the compiler will focus on bug fixing and adding some VO compatibility options which are listed below as well as adding some new features.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Below is the complete (but short) list of things that are not supported yet or are known problems in the current build of X#.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Compiler</para>
    <list id="4" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="List" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="List">Some VO <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="X-Compiler-Options-By-Category">compatibility compiler options</link> are not implemented yet. The command line options are recognized but nothing is done with them<br/>/cs: Case Sensitivity (the compiler is now always Case Insensitive)<br/>/vo 11: VO Compatible Numeric conversions</li>
      <li styleclass="List">The compiler pragmas (#pragma warnings and #pragma options) do not work. They are ignored by the compiler.</li>
      <li styleclass="List">Parser errors need improvements<br/>Erroneous code may generate compiler runtime errors</li>
      <li styleclass="List">Compiler errors may be cryptic every now and then</li>
      <li styleclass="List">The compiler is case insensitive. There may be a problem with case insensitive matching of interface member names. The case insensitivity cannot be switched off for now. <br/>We have also seen problems for classes where different member names are defined with a name that is only different in case. </li>
      <li styleclass="List">Sometimes you may see a &quot;Include file not found&quot; error, where the file DOES exist. This seems to be a side effect of the codepage that was used to save the include files. <br/>When you save the file as UTF8 (File Advanced Save Options in Visual Studio) then this problem almost always disappears.</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Visual Studio</para>
    <list id="5" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="List" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="List">New features in the Debugger, such as a window for Globals and RDD Workareas</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">VO Xporter</para>
    <list id="6" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="List" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="List">DbServer and Fieldspec binaries are not exported yet</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Runtime</para>
    <list id="7" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="List" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="List"><text styleclass="Normal">The DBFCDX RDD is missing</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal">Some runtime functions are not supported yet<br/></li>
    </list>
  </body>
</topic>
