<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>MEMVAR</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>MEMVAR</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">MEMVAR</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The MEMVAR statement is NOT available in the Core and Vulcan dialects and will only be enabled if the <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="opt-memvar">-memvar</link> commandline option is specified.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">memvar &#160; &#160; &#160;: </text><text style="font-weight:bold; font-style:normal; color:#3366ff;">MEMVAR</text><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">&#32;</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Identifiers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">identifier</link><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;"> (, </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Identifiers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">identifier</link><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">)* </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Helpers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">eos</link><br/></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The MEMVAR statement declares variables for the compiler as dynamic memory variables. Such variables belong to the storage class PRIVATE or PUBLIC, and are generated at runtime. With MEMVAR, the compiler can resolve references for variables which were neither declared as LOCAL or STATIC nor are preceded by an alias name and alias operator. The variables in the list are implicitly aliased with MEMVAR-&gt;, the alias for dynamic memory variables. MEMVAR only applies to variables which are referenced at compile time and not at runtime with the macro operator (&amp;). </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The maximum length of a variable name in the list &lt;MemvarName,...&gt; is not limited. <br/>Variables names must consist of alphanumeric characters and the first character cannot be numeric. The underscore (_) is permitted as a special character. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The scope of the MEMVAR statement is the method, function or procedure in which it occurs. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">When the MEMVAR statement occurs at the beginning of the file, prior to any executable statement, its scope is the entire PRG file. It serves exclusively for the declaration of variables and does not create them or verify their existence. The variables are created by the statement PARAMETERS, PRIVATE or PUBLIC. A runtime error occurs if a MEMVAR is referenced prior to being created. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The MEMVAR statement serves for the correct compile time referencing of variables that do not have alias identifiers, and that are not declared as LOCAL, STATIC or as field variables. </para>
  </body>
</topic>
