<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>-checked</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>-checked</keyword>
    <keyword>-checked</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">-checked</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The -checked option specifies whether an integer arithmetic statement that results in a value that is outside the range of the data type, and that is not in the scope of a checked or unchecked keyword, causes a run-time exception.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Syntax</para>
    <para styleclass="Code with box">-checked[+ | -] <text styleclass="Normal">&#32;</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Remarks</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">An integer arithmetic statement that is in the scope of a checked or unchecked keyword is not subject to the effect of The -checked option.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If an integer arithmetic statement that is not in the scope of a checked or unchecked keyword results in a value outside the range of the data type, and -checked+ (/checked) is used in the compilation, that statement causes an exception at run time. If -checked- is used in the compilation, that statement does not cause an exception at run time.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The default value for this option is -checked-. One scenario for using -checked- is in building large applications. Sometimes automated tools are used to build such applications, and such a tool might automatically set -checked to +. You can override the tool&apos;s global default by specifying -checked-.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The VO Compatibility compiler options<link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="opt-ovf"> -ovf</link> and <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="opt-fovf">-fovf</link> both set this option</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">To set this compiler option in the Visual Studio development environment</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <list id="1" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px; font-family:Arial; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">Open the project&apos;s Properties page.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">Click the Build property page.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">Add the option in the &quot;User-Defined Command Line options&quot; property</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Example</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The following command compiles <text styleclass="Code Example">t2.prg</text>. The use of <text styleclass="Code Example">-checked</text> in the command specifies that any integer arithmetic statement in the file that is not in the scope of a checked or unchecked keyword, and that results in a value that is outside the range of the data type, causes an exception at run time.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code with box">xsc t2.prg -checked &#160;</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
