<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-06-29T19:12:29.262+02:00" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>-noinit</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>$Exit</keyword>
    <keyword>$Init1</keyword>
    <keyword>$Init2</keyword>
    <keyword>$Init3</keyword>
    <keyword>EXIT PROCEDURE</keyword>
    <keyword>INIT PROCEDURE</keyword>
    <keyword>-noinit</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">-noinit</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Suppress generation of empty $Init1() and $Exit() functions</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Background info</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The X# compiler generates special functions in each assembly that are used to call INIT procedures and EXIT procedures.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">There are 3 levels of INIT procedures. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">For each of these 3 levels a special function is created: $Init1(), $Init2() and $Init3(). For EXIT procedures the compiler creates a function $Exit().</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The functions $Init2() and $Init3() are only created when needed.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The functions $Init1() and $Exit() are always created.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When you compile an EXE with X# then the compiler generates code that calls the $Init1(), $Init2() and $Init3() functions in all referenced assemblies at startup and the $Exit() functions at shutdown.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">This mechanism also guarantees that classes in referenced assemblies are available at runtime, even when you have not explicitly referenced them in your code, so you can instantiate these classes with CreateInstance().</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The compiler option -noinit suppresses the generation of empty $Init1() and $Exit() functions. As a result there will be no hard link to external assemblies if you do not reference code from these assemblies. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If you use these compiler option with an assembly that only contains DEFINES then the defines will be resolved at compile time and you will not need to include the assembly at runtime (unless these defines contain values that need to be resolved at runtime, such as symbols or date values).</para>
  </body>
</topic>
