<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>-vo13</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>-vo13</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">-vo13<tab />Compatible String Comparisons </para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The -vo13 option enables VO compatible string comparisons</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Syntax</para>
    <para styleclass="Code with box">-vo13[+|-]</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Arguments</para>
    <para styleclass="List">+ | - <tab />Specifying +, or just -vo13, tells the compiler that string comparisons are to be performed the same way as they are in VO, and in the RDDs, where the comparison depends on the SetCollation() setting. &#160;When - is specified, or -vo13 is not specified, string comparisons in code use String.Compare() </para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Remarks</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When this option is enabled string comparisions are compatible with VO and the RDDs, and depend on SetCollation() as follows:</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When collation=#WINDOWS, string comparisons make use of services provided by Windows that automatically handle foreign character sets. These string comparisons are implemented with a call to CompareStringA() function in kernel32.dll.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When collation = #CLIPPER, comparisons are performed byte by byte, using a weight table for each char. As in VO, a different table can be selected with the SetNatDll() function. <br/>In .Net we are using the runtime DLL for the weight tables. In the runtime the nation DLLs are not physically implemented as separate files; the weighting tables are embedded as resources inside XSharp.Core.dll.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When collation = #Unicode then the comparisons will be done with the normal String.Compare() routine that uses the current culture.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When collation = #Ordinal then the comparisons will be done with the normal String.Compare() routine using an ordinal comparison (this is the fastest)</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When -v013 is not enabled string comparisons are performed using String.Compare(), where the comparison makes use of culture-sensitive sort rules according to the current culture selected.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The setting for -vo13 is registered with the runtime by the main application at startup. <text styleclass="List">If you library is compiled with -vo13+ but the main app isn&apos;t, then the string comparisons called from the library will follow the same rules as the main app because the main app registers -vo13 setting with the runtime and the stringcomparison routines in the runtime now detect that the main app does not want to do VO compatible string comparisons. </text><br/><text styleclass="List">We therefore recommend that 3rd party products always enable -vo13.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Compatibility Note: </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When using -vo13 string comparisons involve converting unicode strings to ansi for compatibility and consequently are slower than with String.Compare().</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">&#32;<text styleclass="Heading3">To set this compiler option in the Visual Studio development environment:</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <list id="1" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px; font-family:Arial; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">Open the project&apos;s Properties page</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">Click the Language tab. </li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">In the Visual Objects Compatibility section, modify the &quot;Compatible string comparisons&quot; property. </li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
