<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>-keycontainer</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>-keycontainer</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">-keycontainer</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Specifies the name of the cryptographic key container.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Syntax</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Code with box">-keycontainer:string <text styleclass="Normal">&#32;</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Arguments</para>
    <para styleclass="List"><text styleclass="Code Example">string</text><tab ->The name of the strong name key container.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Remarks</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When The -keycontainer option is used, the compiler creates a sharable component by inserting a public key from the specified container into the assembly manifest and signing the final assembly with the private key. To generate a key file, type sn -k file at the command line. sn -i installs the key pair into a container.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If you compile with -target:module, the name of the key file is held in the module and incorporated into the assembly when you compile this module into an assembly with -addmodule.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can also specify this option as a custom attribute (System.Reflection.AssemblyKeyNameAttribute) in the source code for any Microsoft intermediate language (MSIL) module.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can also pass your encryption information to the compiler with -keyfile. Use -delaysign if you want the public key added to the assembly manifest but want to delay signing the assembly until it has been tested.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">For more information, see Creating and Using Strong-Named Assemblies and Delay Signing an Assembly.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">To set this compiler option in the Visual Studio development environment</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <list id="1" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px; font-family:Arial; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;">This compiler option is not available in the Visual Studio development environment.</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:13px;"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can programmatically access this compiler option with AssemblyKeyContainerName.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
