<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="robert" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>PUBLIC</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>PUBLIC</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">PUBLIC</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The PUBLIC statement is NOT available in the Core and Vulcan dialects and will only be enabled if the <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="opt-memvar">-memvar</link> commandline option is specified.</para>
    <para styleclass="Code Example"><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">public &#160; &#160; &#160;: </text><text style="font-weight:bold; font-style:normal; color:#3366ff;">PUBLIC</text><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">&#32;</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Identifiers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">identifier</link><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;"> (, </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Identifiers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">identifier</link><text style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">)* </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Helpers" style="font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000;">eos</link><br/></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Description </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The PUBLIC statement generates variables which belong to the storage class PUBLIC. Storage classes define the lifetime and visibility of variables. With the PUBLIC statement, so called &quot;dynamic&quot; variables are created at runtime. The PUBLIC statement belongs to the executable statements. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The declaration of a PUBLIC variable takes place with the declaration MEMVAR. The creation of such a variable takes place with the statement PUBLIC. Since the symbolic names of PUBLIC variables exist at runtime, they can be saved in files with the SAVE command and can be restored at runtime. PUBLIC variables can also be dynamically created from character string expressions using the macro operator (&amp;) at runtime. This cannot be done with LOCAL or STATIC variables. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The variable name for the PUBLIC may occur only once within a function. This includes variables which are declared as STATIC or as LOCAL. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The length of a variable name is unlimited. A variable name consists of alphanumeric characters, and the first character may not be numeric. The underscore (_) is permitted as a special character. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">The lifetime of a PUBLIC variable extends implicitly to the entire lifetime of a program. It is released upon program termination, but can also explicitly be deleted with one of the commands CLEAR ALL, CLEAR MEMORY or RELEASE. A PUBLIC variable remains globally visible. It can, if necessary, be &quot;hidden&quot; by a new variable with the same variable name which belongs to the storage class PRIVATE, LOCAL or STATIC. As soon as the &quot;new&quot; variable is no longer visible or no longer exists, the PUBLIC variable becomes visible again. </para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text">A PUBLIC variable initially has the value NIL.</para>
    <para styleclass="Body Text"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
